My theme for this month’s broadcast is
今月のブロードキャストの主題は—
“Young Ones
—Build Your Future With Jehovah!”
“若い皆さん エホバと共に
将来を築きましょう！”です
If you do,
1 Timothy 6:19 assures
そうするなら
テモテ第一6章19節にある通り—
that you will
‘safely treasure up for yourself
“自分のため 将来に対する
りっぱな土台を安全に蓄え—”
a fine foundation for the future,’
and you will
“get a firm hold on the real life.”
“真の命をしっかりとらえる”ことに
なるでしょう
Obviously, we will be directing
many of our comments
もちろん わたしたちはこの話を—
エホバの組織にいる愛する若い皆さんに
直接語りかけたいと思っています
directly to you dear young ones
in Jehovah’s organization.
Yet, if we think about it,
でも 考えてみると—
all of us figuratively
わたしたちが生きたいと願っている
永遠という時間と比べると—
are very young ones
compared to eternity
わたしたちは皆
比喩的に言って若者です
—how long we hope to live.
So, in a sense,
our comments during this broadcast
ですからある意味で—
このブロードキャストで話されることは
わたしたち皆に当てはまります
have application to all of us.
Personally, I am so thankful to Jehovah
高校卒業後すぐに
開拓奉仕をするようにとの—
that positive peer pressure
was put on me
積極的な仲間の圧力があったことを
わたしは個人的に
エホバに感謝しています
to enter the pioneer ministry
right out of high school.
What a blessing and a protection
それはわたしにとって祝福であり
保護になりました
it was to enter
the regular pioneer work
17歳で正規開拓奉仕を始め—
at age 17
18歳でベテルに行くことが
できたのです
and to be able to go to Bethel at 18.
Even though there was considerable
worldly pressure put on me
大学教育を追い求めるようにとの—
周囲からのかなりの圧力が
ありましたが—
to pursue university education,
I am so happy that with Jehovah’s help,
エホバの助けのおかげで—
エホバと共に将来を築くという決定が
できたのは大きな喜びです
I decided to build my future
with Jehovah.
Truly, I have no regrets.
わたしは何も後悔していません
And this is always true of young ones
心からエホバに仕えている若者たちも
同様に感じています
who serve Jehovah from their hearts
—they have no regrets.
後悔などはしていません
In fact, you will enjoy
these expressions from young ones
それでは エホバと共に将来を築いている
若者たちの声をお聞きください
who are building
their future with Jehovah.
Before I started pioneering,
開拓を始める前は 毎月
時間が入るか不安でした
I was really nervous that I wouldn’t be able
to get my time in every month.
It was a bit hard when I started pioneering
because I didn’t have a car.
車がなかったから
始めるのはちょっと大変でした
My boss,
he didn’t give me part-time work.
上司はパートを
認めてくれませんでした
I found it really hard
to balance schoolwork
学校と開拓の両立は大変でした
and pioneering
at the same time.
My biggest struggle was fear of man,
so that really hindered me
一番の障害は人への恐れでした
人と話すのが苦手だったからです
because I wasn’t very good
at talking to people.
Having a good routine was a struggle.
良い習慣を持つのに苦労しました
My brother and I are
the only ones in the truth.
真理にいるのは兄とわたしだけです
My family didn’t understand
なんで奉仕に行きたいのか
家族に理解してもらえませんでした
why we wanted to go preaching.
I didn’t think
that I’d make a good pioneer.
できるとは思えませんでした
I’ve had Type 1 diabetes
since I was five.
5歳の時からⅠ型の糖尿病なので—
So I was always worried
about whether or not
健康と開拓のバランスが取れるか
いつも心配でした
I could balance that health condition
with pioneering.
The challenges
don’t seem that big now,
今と比べて以前は
もっと問題が大きかったんです
but back at that time
they were a really big deal.
エホバの助けがすご過ぎです
But the coolest thing
was how Jehovah helped me.
Prayer to Jehovah
helped me overcome my fears.
祈って恐れを克服しました
My family was
a massive help from Jehovah.
家族はエホバからの強力な助けです
Because my dad was the one
who first encouraged me to pioneer,
開拓を最初に励ましてくれたのは父です
when I did start pioneering,
he promised that I would have
家族からのフルサポートを
約束してくれました
the full support of my family.
When I spoke to brothers and sisters
who spent their youth
若いときに全時間奉仕をした
兄弟姉妹と話すことが—
in the full-time service
that really helped me
大きな助けになりました
because it was really encouraging,
and it really motivated me
すごく力をもらって—
わたしも全時間奉仕を経験したい
っていう気持ちになりました
to want to make my own memories
and my own experiences
in the full-time service.
So there were
practical things I could do.
できることをしました
車がないから 歩くかバスに乗りました
I didn’t have a car;
I just walked or I caught the bus.
I had to work out
what my priorities were first.
優先順位を決めました
So I had to find out how many hours
would I have to go witnessing every week.
毎週 何時間奉仕すべきか考えました
それから 曜日ごとに いつ奉仕して
いつ学校に行くか計画を立てました
So then I just sat down
and I looked at every day
and planned out which days
I could go witnessing,
which days I had to go to school,
宿題とか研究する時間も
取れるようにしました
and also allocated time
so that I could do my homework and study.
Having a schedule
was really good
予定を立ててよかったです
because I could see it
all out in front of me,
やることを全部書きだしてみたら—
and I could see
that the hour requirement
要求時間を達成できるって分かって
無理って思わなくなりました
was actually attainable,
so that made it a lot less daunting.
I first set short-term goals of pioneering
in the special months of activity.
初めは 特別活動の月に
開拓をする短期的な目標を持ちました
Then I was able
to begin continuous auxiliary,
それから 連続で補助をして
最終的に正規開拓を始めました
and then eventually
I started regular pioneering.
One of the best things I did
to prepare myself for pioneering
すごくよかった開拓の準備は
補助開拓です
was to auxiliary pioneer beforehand.
開拓をしながら
直面するどんな困難も—
It really set me up
to be able to overcome
克服できるよう準備できました
any challenges
that I faced while I was pioneering.
I thought about Malachi 3:10.
マラキ 3章10節を考えました
I knew I trusted in Jehovah,
エホバを信頼していたけど
試みるいい機会でした
but this was my chance
to test him out.
I prayed,
put my trust in Jehovah,
祈って エホバを信頼し
申し込みました
and put my application in.
After my form
was in for pioneering,
開拓者になってしばらくして
ある兄弟が仕事をくれました
a brother, with time,
a brother called me and offered me work.
I had unemployment
for three months,
3か月仕事がなかったから大変でした
which wasn’t a good time.
でも その間に
エホバに注意を集中しました
But during that time,
I had Jehovah as my main focus.
エホバは支えてくださって
見捨てたりされませんでした
And so he supported me,
and he didn’t let me down.
Asking brothers and sisters to come
奉仕する人が少ない日に—
and work with me,
maybe on days that I knew
兄弟姉妹に一緒に働くよう
お願いしました
that I wouldn’t get as much support,
really helped.
すごく助けになりました
That helped me to organize
my hours a little bit more,
もっと時間を活用できるし
兄弟姉妹をよく知ることもできます
and also I’d get to know
my brothers and sisters more as well.
One of the greatest joys of pioneering
has been to pioneer with Mum.
すごく嬉しいのは
母と開拓ができることです
And we had the privilege of going
同じ開拓者学校に行けて
とてもよかったです
to the pioneer school together,
which was really special.
Psalm 16:8 reminds me
詩編 16編8節からエホバが
すぐそばにいてくださると分かります
that Jehovah is right beside me.
When I’m preaching,
it’s like Jehovah is holding my hand.
奉仕のとき
手を握ってくださっているみたいです
So with full-time service,
I love making Jehovah happy.
全時間奉仕をして
エホバを喜ばせたいです
与えられたものすべてを用いて
やっと少しお返しできます
With everything that he has given me,
I’m finally able to give something back.
Looking back
—pioneering—
振り返れば
開拓は今までで最善の決定です
it was the best decision
I’ve ever made.
It’s opened up
so many different avenues
エホバへのいろんな
奉仕の道が開かれます
of service to Jehovah,
また 全時間奉仕を続ける
真の願いを持つ助けにもなります
and it helped me also
to have that real desire
to want to stay
in full-time service.
Helping someone
on the road to everlasting life,
道行く人を永遠の命へ導くのは
最高です
it’s the best feeling ever;
and it’s really irreplaceable.
何にも代えられません
The only thing I can say,
勧めたいことはただ1つ—
“As a young person, start pioneering!”
“若いうちに 開拓奉仕！”
What a fine attitude
those young ones have!
何と立派な態度ではないでしょうか？
They are clearly following
in Jesus’ footsteps.
この若者たちは
イエスのあとに従っています
Jesus was the wisest man
イエスは地上で最も賢い人でした
who ever walked the earth.
He could’ve pursued any career
どんな職業にも優れた能力を
発揮できたでしょう
and truly excelled at it.
He could’ve been
the greatest carpenter who ever lived.
世界で最高の大工になれたはずです
Think about it,
イエスは父を助けて
物質の宇宙を造りました
he helped his Father
build the physical universe.
Can you imagine
what kind of houses he could’ve built?
どんな家を建てることができたか
想像できますか？
Or what if he had pursued
being an inventor?
発明家になっていたら
どうでしょうか？
With his perfect brain,
完全な頭脳を使って—
he probably could’ve invented
the telephone,
電話や車やコンピューターを
西暦1世紀に発明できたことでしょう
automobile, or computer
in the first century.
Or what about becoming
a businessman?
ビジネスマンになっていたら
どうでしょう？
With perfect intelligence,
he likely could’ve come out on top
完璧な知性を使って—
自分がかかわった
あらゆる商業取引から利益を上げ—
of every business transaction
that he entered,
becoming the richest businessman
who ever lived.
世界一の大富豪になることが
できたでしょう
Or have you ever thought about
あるいは運動選手になっていたら
どうだったか考えたことがありますか？
if he had pursued becoming
an athlete?
And excelling in athletic contests
イエスの時代 運動競技で勝つためには
大きな努力が求められました
was a huge endeavor in Jesus’ day.
With a little training,
it is likely that his perfect body
完全な体を持つイエスは
ほんのわずかな訓練で—
would have outperformed all people
不完全な体を持つ—
他のすべての選手よりも
優れたパフォーマンスをして—
with imperfect bodies,
enabling him to become
世界で最も優れた運動選手に
なったことでしょう
the most famous athlete who ever lived.
Or one more example,
もう一つの例です
what if he had decided to become a doctor?
イエスが医者になっていたら
どうでしょう？
He could cure sick people
病気の人を癒し—
死者を生き返らせることも
できたでしょう
—even raise the dead.
Can you imagine how much
he could’ve charged rich people
人を生き返らせるとどれくらいの料金を
お金持ちから請求できたと思いますか？
to raise their dead loved ones?
でも イエスは
このいずれをも追い求めませんでした
But Jesus pursued none of these careers.
Why?
なぜですか？
Because he knew
that any of such endeavors
それは イエスがこのいずれもが—
would have only very limited
非常に限られた一時的な益しか
もたらさないことを知っていたからです
and temporary benefits.
Instead, he pursued something
代わりに イエスはより多くの人に
永続的な益をもたらすもの—
he knew would bring far-reaching
and everlasting benefits:
つまり全時間宣教を追い求めました
the full-time ministry.
If this is how the wisest man
who ever walked the earth—
地上で最も賢い人が推論して
そう結論したのであれば—
If this is how he reasoned,
わたしたちも同じように考えて
賢い者であることを示せるでしょう
we are wise if we strive to think
the same way.
That makes me think of the comments
以前 巡回奉仕をしていた時に会った—
of a well-adjusted teenage brother
良く訓練された十代の兄弟の
語ったことを思い出しました
whom we served
while in the circuit work many years ago.
This young brother went straight into
the regular pioneer work
この若い兄弟は 高校卒業後すぐに
正規開拓奉仕を始めました
out of high school,
and I asked him why he did so.
わたしはなぜそうしたのか
聞いてみました
He explained that he knew
he could’ve gotten a full-time secular job
兄弟が言うには—
and bought a new car for himself,
全時間の仕事について
自分で新車を買うこともできるけれど—
but he reasoned that in a few years
数年もたてば車はさびてダメになるし—
that car would rust out and break down,
そうしたら何も残らなくなるって
考えたそうです
and he would have nothing.
But he knew that he could go
into the pioneer work
でも 兄弟は開拓奉仕を始めて
エホバとの近しい関係を築き—
and build a close relationship with Jehovah
and perhaps even find
an honest-hearted person
心の正直な人々を見つけて—
真理を教えることができるかもしれない
ことを知っていました
and be able to teach that one the truth.
And he knew that would last forever.
そして それが永続する益をもたらす
ことを知っていたのです
Now, that is some wise thinking
この若い兄弟がそう考えたのは
賢明なことです
on the part of that young brother.
And today, that brother
has a beautiful Christian wife
この兄弟には
美しいクリスチャンの妻と—
幾人かの霊的な子どもたちがおり—
and several spiritual children,
いま兄弟は立派な長老として
奉仕しています
and he is serving as a fine elder.
But if you young ones
are going to think this way
でも若い皆さん このように考え
霊的な目標を追い求めたいなら—
and continue to pursue spiritual goals,
it is vital that you wisely choose
自分の友を賢く選ぶことは大切です
your associates.
In a sense, our associates
ある意味 友はエレベーターに
例えることができます
can be likened to an elevator.
What do we mean?
どういう意味でしょう？
Well, they can take you up
あなたを引き上げたり
引き降ろしたりするということです
or they can take you down.
If you choose wisely,
賢明に選ぶなら
引き上げてくれます
they will take you up
—elevate your good qualities
良い特質を伸ばし
より良い人にならせてくれます
and make you a better person.
But if you choose poorly,
でも まずい選択をすると
引き降ろされるのです
they will take you down.
Depending on how badly you choose,
選択がどれほどまずいかによって—
they can take you way down
地下室まで—
—to the basement,
場合によっては—
even the subbasement.
地下2階にまで
引きずり降ろされてしまいます
箴言13章20節で—
At Proverbs 13:20,
わたしたちを造られた愛ある天の父は
その点をこう説明されました
our loving heavenly Father,
who made us,
explains how it works.
エホバはこう述べておられます
Jehovah tells us there:
“The one walking with the wise
“賢い者たちと共に歩んでいる者は
賢くなり—”
“will become wise,
“but the one
who has dealings with the stupid
“愚鈍な者たちと交渉を持つ者は
苦しい目に遭う”
will fare badly.”
“Walking with”
“共に歩む”とか“交渉を持つ”とは
“友になる”と言う意味です
and “having dealings with”
mean “associating with.”
And who are the “stupid” ones?
では“愚鈍な者”とはだれですか？
Well, this scripture contrasts
such a person
この聖句はそのような人を
賢い人と対比しています
with those who are wise.
It is not talking about someone
who lacks mental intellect.
それは勉強ができない人のことでは
ありません
It is talking about someone
それはエホバの基準からして—
who does not make
wise decisions spiritually
霊的に賢い決定をしない人のことを
述べているのです
from Jehovah’s standpoint.
そう考えると—
And if we think about it,
少なくとも今のこの時に
エホバに仕えようとしていない人は—
anyone who is not really serving Jehovah
だれであれ全く賢い人ではありません
—at least right now—
that one is unwise indeed.
そしてそのような人たちと
いつも一緒にいるなら—
And if we associate closely with such ones,
エホバは“苦しい目に遭う”と
述べておられます
Jehovah says that we “will fare badly.”
別の例えを考えてみましょう
We could use another illustration.
Think about someone who is physically sick
病気にかかっていて
高熱のある人がいるとします
and is running a high fever.
If we spend a lot of time with that person,
その人と長い時間共に過ごすなら
同じ病気にかかってしまうことでしょう
we will probably catch the same sickness.
Or worse,
もっと悪いことに—
if we spend a lot of time
near a dead body—a corpse—
死んだ人つまり死体のそばに
長時間いるなら—
we will probably pick up a disease.
病気に感染することでしょう
Well, it is similar
霊的に病気の人 さらに悪いことに
霊的に死んでいる人と—
with spending time with a person
who is spiritually sick,
時間を過ごすことについても
同じことが言えます
or worse, spiritually dead.
On the other hand,
if we choose as our associates
一方 エホバを愛し エホバと共に—
those who love Jehovah
永遠の将来を築こうとしている人々を
友として選ぶなら—
and who are building
their everlasting future with Jehovah,
わたしたちは
大いに益を受けることができます
we will benefit greatly.
Please observe carefully
this variety of young ones
エホバと共に忙しく
天に宝を蓄えている—
次の様々な若者たちのことを
どうぞ注意深くご覧ください
who are busy storing up
treasures in heaven
with Jehovah.
How heartwarming it is to us
これらのりっぱな若者たちが—
—and we know it is to Jehovah—
イエスの次の勧めを
実践しているのを見るのは—
to see these beautiful young people
わたしたちにとって
心温まるものですが—
doing what Jesus encourages
それはエホバにとってもそうでしょう
at Matthew 6:20, 21.
それはマタイ 6章20，21節
の言葉です
There, Jesus encourages:
イエスはこう言われました
“Store up for yourselves
treasures in heaven,
“自分のために天に宝を蓄えなさい”
“そこでは蛾もさびも食わず”
“where neither moth nor rust consumes,
“盗人が押し入って
盗むこともありません”
“and where thieves do not break in and steal.
“あなたの宝のある所
そこにあなたの心もあるのです”
“For where your treasure is,
there your heart will be also.”
And if we think about it,
色々考えてきましたが
結局のところ—
in the final analysis,
老若を問わず わたしたちの真価は—
after all is said and done,
whether we are younger or older,
エホバと共に何を天に蓄えたか
ということになります
our net worth will be
what we have stored up
in heaven with Jehovah.
We will not be able to take
material treasures with us
物質の宝を持って
大患難を通過することはできません
through the great tribulation.
And if we die,
死んでしまうなら
物質の宝を持って行くことなどできません
we certainly will not be able to take
material treasures with us,
しかし 霊的な宝は
大患難を通過するときも
but we can take spiritual treasures
with us through the great tribulation
死と復活を経験したとしても
携えて行くことができます
and even through death and resurrection.
It is true with all of Jehovah’s people,
啓示14章13節は—
as it is with the anointed,
油そそがれた者についても
すべてのエホバの民にも当てはまります
what is stated at Revelation 14:13.
そこには “彼らの行なったことは
そのまま彼らに伴って行く”とあります
It says there:
“The things they did go right with them.”
And how encouraging it is
若い皆さんがバプテスマを受けるのを
見ると本当に大きな励みになります
to see young ones getting baptized
—publicly demonstrating
それは自分の命をエホバにささげたことを
公に示すことです
that they are giving their lives to Jehovah.
And we sincerely hope
まだバプテスマを受けていない
若い皆さんが資格をとらえたならすぐ—
that you young ones
who are not yet baptized
will not hold back from getting baptized
バプテスマを受けることを
ちゅうちょしないように—
心からお勧めしたいと思います
as soon as you qualify.
The sooner you can get baptized,
バプテスマを早く受ければ
それだけ早く—
the sooner you will receive
greater protection
エホバからの大きな保護と祝福を
受けることができるのです
and blessings from Jehovah.
Not long ago,
it made me very happy
それほど昔のことではありませんが—
10歳のかわいい兄弟がバプテスマを
受けたのを見てとてもうれしく思いました
to observe a little ten-year-old brother
get baptized!
And young ones,
若い皆さん
自分がエホバの証人であることを—
never be afraid to identify yourselves
明らかにすることを
決して恐れないでください
as one of Jehovah’s Witnesses.
Never allow the fear
of what others may think
ほかの人がどう思うかと恐れて
自分のことを隠してはなりません
to cause you to hesitate to do so.
Jehovah tells us
エホバは箴言29章25節で
こう述べておられます
at Proverbs 29:25:
“Trembling at men is a snare,
“人に対するおののきは わなとなる”
“しかし エホバに依り頼んでいる者は
保護される“
“but the one trusting in Jehovah
will be protected.”
Many years ago when I was in school,
ずっと昔 学校にいたころのことですが—
I can remember being
at times somewhat worried
時々クラスメイトは自分のことを
どう思っているのだろうかと—
about how my fellow classmates
would view me.
不安な気持ちになったことがありました
But then a little while later,
でも それから少したって
卒業しましたが—
I got out of school
and never ever again even saw
わたしは以前のクラスメートのほとんどに
一度も会ったことがありません
most of those former classmates.
Then it dawned on me
それで気づいたのですが—
人が自分の事をどう思うかは
本当は重要ではないのです
that it doesn’t really matter
what people think about us.
It is Jehovah’s rating of us
エホバがどう思われるかが重要なのです
that truly counts.
Humans cannot add
人間は寿命を5秒たりとも
延ばすことはできませんが—
even five seconds to our lifespan,
but Jehovah can add
エホバは永遠を人に与えたり
取り去ったりできるのです
or subtract eternity.
エホバだけが
真の幸福を与えることができる方です
And he alone
can also give us true happiness.
And as Proverbs 29:25 indicates,
箴言 29章25節が
示しているように—
what a protection
it is to courageously identify ourselves
勇気をもって自分がエホバの証人で
あることを明らかにし—
as one of Jehovah’s Witnesses,
エホバを全く信頼して
エホバにしっかり付くなら—
fully trusting Jehovah
and taking our stand solidly with him.
それはわたしたちにとって
素晴らしい保護となります
Never be ashamed of who you are.
自分がだれであるかを
決して恥じてはなりません
You are one of Jehovah’s Witnesses.
あなたはエホバの証人なのです
And please, dear young ones,
愛する若い皆さん
we warmly encourage you
皆さんを愛している人たちの
言うことを聞いてください
to listen to those who love you.
エホバ神は皆さんを愛しています
Jehovah loves you very much;
the Governing Body loves you very much;
統治体も皆さんを愛しています
the elders love you very much;
長老たちもそうです
your Christian parents love you very much.
クリスチャンの親たちもそうです
And these ones will tell you the truth,
これらの人たちは
あなたに真理を語ります
even though at times
あなたが聞きたくないと
思うようなことも語ります
it may not be what you want to hear.
They will not ‘tickle your ears,’
これらの人たちは—
あなたの“耳をくすぐる”ようなことは
言いません
perhaps like ones at school
or in the neighborhood
本当はあなたを愛しておらず
あなたの最善を願っていない—
who don’t really love you
学校の友達や近所の人たちとは
違うのです
or have your best interests at heart.
But please believe those
でも あなたを愛しているからこそ—
who will tell you the truth
あなたに真理を語る
これらの人たちを信じてください
because they love you.
And never view
Jehovah’s laws and principles
そして エホバの律法や原則のために—
何か良いものを得損なっている
とは決して思わないでください
as depriving you of something good.
View them as protecting you
それはあなたを傷つけるものから
あなたを守っているのです
from what will hurt you.
If you recall,
思い出してください
Satan convinced Eve
サタンは
エホバが制限を設けているために—
that she was being deprived by Jehovah
何か良いものを得損なっていると
エバに思い込ませました
and was missing out on something good.
Now, it is true that Eve
was missing out on something.
エバが何かを得損なっていたのは
本当です
But what was she really missing out on?
でも実際には
何を得損なっていたでしょうか？
A tormented conscience,
良心の呵責に苦しむこと—
her beautiful hair turning gray,
美しい髪が白髪になること—
her teeth falling out,
歯が抜け落ちること—
her perfect skin wrinkling up like a prune,
もち肌に深いしわが生じること—
being bent over from old age,
年と共に腰が曲がること—
hobbling around on a cane,
杖をついてよぼよぼになること—
and finally dying!
最後に死を迎えることです
But Satan convinced her
サタンはエホバが何かを奪っていると
エバに思い込ませました
that Jehovah was depriving her,
so foolishly she reached out to get
愚かにも—
エバはいわば自分が得損なっていると
思ったものを得るようになったのです
what she thought she was missing out on.
Well, Satan will try to use
サタンはあなたにも同様の策略を
用いようとするでしょう
the same kind of strategy on you,
but please don’t let him do it!
でも決してそうさせてはなりません
This also makes me think
of an experience a brother once related.
先ほどお話しした兄弟の経験を
思い起こします
He said that he was visiting
an animal observatory,
兄弟によると
ある動物観察施設に行った時のこと—
and a large lion lunged toward him
大きなライオンが
兄弟に向かって突進してきました
but was prevented from reaching him
でも 動物とその施設を隔てていた
分厚いガラスのおかげで—
by a thick glass pane
separating the animals from the observers.
ライオンは来ることができませんでした
As the lion stood on his hind legs,
ライオンは後ろ脚で立ちあがり
爪でガラスをひっかき—
clawing the glass
大きな牙をむき出していました
and baring his massive teeth,
the brother came to realize in a special way
兄弟はその保護バリアのありがたさを
特別な仕方で実感しました
the protective value of that barrier.
Previously, he said
that he somewhat viewed the glass pane
兄弟によると ガラスに汚れが
ついていると良く見えないので—
as a restriction
それまでは そのガラスの塀は
余計なものと見ていました
because the smudges on it
partially blurred his view,
but now he viewed it
でも 今では本当に保護するものだと
みなすようになりました
as a real protection.
Well, in a similar way,
同様にサタンは—
Jehovah doesn’t want Satan,
ペテロ第一 5章8節で—
who is described
as ‘a roaring, devouring lion’
“ほえて歩き回る”ライオン
として描かれています
at 1 Peter 5:8—
それでエホバは若い人たちがサタンに
むさぼり食われるようなことを—
He doesn’t want him
to gobble down you young ones.
願ってはおられません
And His laws and principles
エホバの律法と原則は
皆さんを守るためのものなのです
are designed to keep that
from happening to you.
So please listen to Jehovah.
どうかエホバの言われることを
聞いてください
He loves you!
エホバはあなたを愛しておられます